The guys at this level are so easy to intimidate.
I don't have to do anything except show my face.
Yoshitsune!
Don't tell me not to want to be like you.
Because, uh...
Because I'm in love with the way you play.
Oh, my.
It doesn't matter what path I'm on or whatever.
Little Mopped Aoi, I'm going to let you in on a little secret, okay?
There's only one player I've seen in my entire career
that may have made me feel the slightest bit jealous.
Literally that much.
Him? Jealous?
There's no way!
Who was it?
Old spiky head Kuribayashi.
And you sort of play like him, you know?
So being like me isn't going to help you.
What? Kuribayashi?
Okay, awkward, but, dude, for the past month or so,
I've been watching old videos of his games to steal all his moves.
That was a pretty good call.
Whatever you're doing, it's working.
I know that I can outscore anyone most of the time.
However, I'm just one player out of 11.
It's not like that for Kuribayashi, though.
Man, he makes my guts churn.
And you remind me of him.
But with curly hair, so that's why.
I am a little bit jealous of you, too.
Like, the slightest bit.
That's insane.
Jealous of me when he plays like that?
But that kind of helps.
You saying you're in love with my game is pretty awesome.
I'll sign an autograph for you later.
Thanks, Mophead!
Ugh.
It should be an easy enough win if they can just get the ball to Yoshitsune again in the
second half, right? That all depends. It's hard to say. Their opponents could surround Yoshitsune
and force the others to take the ball, and none of them are playing well today. Not an ideal
situation when up against a strong Tokyo Metropolis League team. Also, relying so much
on one player wouldn't be smart. I hope they know that and adjust their tactics in the next half.
Yoshitsune is a temporary player. They need to try scoring without counting on him. That
would benefit the team overall.
Makes sense.
Whoa, what's wrong?
My knees just straight up cave out. It's wild that such a fierce player would be giving himself
a tune-up on the B team, you know?
Right! So take lots of pictures, okay? That's gonna be an awesome article!
Hana, when it comes to soccer, you really don't know much, do you?
Are we all clear? Nothing changes. Just get that ball to Yoshitsune. We can't have a
fifth consecutive loss, so suck it up and let him be the star.
What are you, Bobby Robson? Those are some weak tactics.
What?
Defenders! Keep on doing what you're doing. Don't slack off.
I think we held out pretty well during the first half. Aoi screwed up some, but overall,
he's improving. As long as we keep going and don't give up, we win. So let's go take it all!
Yeah!
Ashito!
Huh?
I'm going on the attack. Trust me. Relying on Yoshitsune to win isn't gonna help us out in the long run.
What are you gonna do? What are you gonna do? I know you're itching. You miss scoring the goals.
Changing it up, are we? They're trying to make it harder for us to get the ball to Yoshitsune at all.
Don't be like me. You're following the path you're supposed to all on your own.
Yeah, but... What if I don't like the path I'm supposed to be on? I want yours! I want to attack!
And now that they're swarming Yoshitsune, there are more open spaces! I could actually score!
Something tells me I might be about to grasp onto something great.
Fukuda, he... he speaks highly of you. To the A-team. You know?
I can always go back to the way I was.
The right wing's open! Head for the space!
There he goes. Tokushi's moving up.
What's with the space on the right wing? It looks different for some reason.
You okay, Ishiki? He's still feeling that injury from the first half.
I'm not gonna let them pass me!
Tokushi? He's gonna catch up at that speed!
If Takashima and I sandwich this guy, we can stop him right there so he can have it!
Huh? Did those defenders just run from the ball?
What the heck was that crap about?
You need to communicate with each other!
It's not that hard! All you had to do was talk to each other!
And just now, you both made a choice not to do that!
We're all playing defense today!
We have to win, and I don't care who does it or how!
Tsukushima, we gotta make some changes to the system.
Togashi, I'm gonna need to talk to you after the game.
Just make a note that from now on, we're gonna give this win all we got!
Huh?
What the heck is going on with those guys?
I cannot believe they made such a stupid mistake!
The second half just started, and the momentum's not on our side at all.
I bet they're gonna pull Ishiki from the game.
That was Asperion's number nine we just saw leaving on a stretcher.
What a time for a new player to come on.
Hey, Shimizu!
Togashi!
What the...
Aoi!
Got that?
Just one more goal for the comeback!
Remember, stay tight on Yoshitsune!
Yeah!
Conceding due to a defensive error, and after a change at center-back,
Isperion's defense sure seems to be falling apart!
All we gotta do is press hard and snatch that ball away!
Wait a minute, something's different!
I see, they've changed their entire system on us!
Ishiki's replacement will be Numizu.
I'll keep him at center-back.
Shimizu, the anchorman, will drop back into the defensive line.
And both fullbacks?
Go upfield.
Both you and Togashi are supposed to fly forward.
That's from Coach Nozomi.
You're still a fullback, though, alright?
So don't forget to defend, okay?
Keep that in mind up there.
Oh, and...
Coach wanted me to give you a message.
He said to tell you,
Attacking from defense isn't a whole new ballgame.
Take what you've learned and apply it to attacking.
That's it.
I can go upfield?
I'm allowed to move upfield and score?
That makes me unbelievably happy!
I'm frickin' stoked!
But is it really that simple?
Whenever I want, while still playing defense?
How do I attack, while still maintaining the back line?
I want to go upfield right now, but...
Damn it!
I don't know what I should be doing!
Ashito!
Hurry up! Let's go!
Stick with me! I could use your support!
Cover the spaces on the right for me, but not too close, okay?
That's a great idea!
Let's go!
Yoshitsune's open!
Ugh!
We fully expected for this game to be tied,
but we had to move the timing up.
Ishiki's injury stopped the game, but we had always planned to alter the formation at this point in the match.
So now, we wait for the players to figure it all out? That right?
Let's hope they've all learned something out there.
What the... Why can't I get the ball?!
I know this feeling. I've been here. It's exactly like the Seikyo High match.
A triangle!
What?
Don't just stand there, go get the ball!
Yeah, right. Good luck trying, you dweebs. The only difference between then and now is I'm in Asuri's position.
Take what you've learned on defense and apply it to attacking.
Their number 19's closing in.
Hurry! Here, Ultimo! Pass it back!
Yoshitsune!
Otimo, I'm trusting you to know how my mind works. Please try to read me. Here it comes!
Do you want to pass? Okay. But where?
I see it!
I'm in the back. And that gives me an advantage.
I can be the eyes for the players in front of me. I'll give them instructions and tell them what they can't see.
I'll tell them exactly how to score like I would!
Watching you enjoy yourself like this makes me very happy too.
The pass got through?
Hey, Ultimo!
He's open in prime position!
I can shoot!
Don't shoot!
That was close. I didn't see him coming. But thanks to that, it looked like a fake out.
Shoot!
Now!
It's clear!
I'm just one player out of eleven. I'm a little bit jealous of you too.
Everyone's one player out of eleven in a game of soccer.
That was weird. What did he mean by that?
I have a direct shot at the goal from here. Just like in the Seikyo High match. I'm farther away than I was then. But the shot's still on.
Huh? Tachibana's completely open. And he's in the perfect spot. Rather than going for the tough shot, I should pass to him.
No, wait. If I nudge it a little to the right, I can avoid the crowd. And take the shot! That's what I'll do.
Come up with four viable options. And out of those four...
I choose.
Ugh!
Eww!
Ah!
Ah, we did it!
Togashi, let's go!
A fullback providing the assist to another fullback?
There's something you don't see every day.
Huh?
Togashi!
You are the best!
The ball came in from behind you,
but that didn't matter to this beast!
You just went flying up high with that header!
Man!
Look at you, scoring despite being a fullback!
Hey, Ashito!
That was a baller assist!
It was the only option.
If we were gonna score, we needed Togashi's height.
Hey, Ashito.
That was a great assist.
Thanks, but what happened to you?
You spaced out.
You were just standing there.
And you were offside.
It's happening again.
That look.
Sweet, and yet fragile.
When it comes to soccer,
you really don't know much, do you?
Yep, it's a world I just don't understand.
Oh, hang on.
Are you leaving?
I just remembered.
I have something for you.
Your photo.
Photo?
From the last game.
I sure got some fun ones.
Sorry for not asking for permission.
It's a thank you for showing me around.
There are two copies.
Give one to Aoi for me, all right?
Thank you!
What's the deal with that kid?
I don't know what it is that triggers him,
but it's like he becomes someone else.
Improvements always welcome,
but from a coach's standpoint,
how far out can you even predict when instructing him?
Nozomi?
I don't think predictions are possible here, Tsukishima.
Fukuda?
You ever been able to predict anything in youth soccer?
Yeah, right.
We're going into stoppage time!
Hold the lead, you guys!
Just a little longer!
You can do it!
HELP NOOOOOOO!
He held on!
Yes!
Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go.
In the end, my last contribution in this game was the assist, the one for Tokushi's goalie.
You had a good assist toward the end there, but after that the balance was totally off.
You racked up miles in the attack, switching from offense to defense over and over again.
It's like you deliberately wore yourself out.
You're right.
After that assist, my mind started to get hazy.
I don't remember what I did right after, much less what happened the rest of the game.
I heard you were killing it on defense, Ashiton.
Nozomi was raving about how you were barking orders effectively, eliminating spaces.
Defense isn't easy.
There are a lot more structural rules than playing on offense.
It takes some hardcore skill to verbalize moves.
But if you're able to shout instructions like you just did,
it means you're able to put those thoughts into words.
You applied that to your attack, and it got you an assist.
I am impressed.
Great job.
Fukuda, he speaks highly of you, to the A-team, you know?
So, uh, help me understand something.
Why didn't you take the shot?
I'm not looking for the right answer, trying to get all judgy about it.
It's just, we won the game and yet it looks an awful lot like you're over here sulking.
It's because I suck.
I'm not only frustrated because I couldn't play consistently for a full 90 minutes,
but I want to be a forward again.
And yet when I was in that moment, I chose to pass instead of scoring.
I have no idea why I did that.
It worked out for you.
Me not taking shots, didn't it?
You branded me as a failed forward and that backs you up.
Quit doubting yourself as a player.
That's the only criticism I'd make.
I wonder why I doubt myself.
Your next opponent is Tokyo Musashino, right?
I've seen videos.
They are one hell of a team, you know?
I don't think you're ready for them yet.
But, depending on how well you do in that match, I might consider moving you to the A-Team.
Good luck.
Ashita!
No! We finally won a game!
And it was all thanks to that assist of yours!
Yeah, and you did really well on defense, Aoi!
Thank you!
Get off!
Yo, Aoi!
Hey, Ishiki! How's your leg?
Don't worry about me. We won. That's all that really matters.
Ow!
Thanks, bro!
Hmm.
How about it, Hana?
That was the first game I played in quite a while!
I'd say you picked a good day to show up, wouldn't you?
You were incredible out there!
Well, I had to be. I knew you were gonna be in the stands.
Huh?
I reserved my premium shiz for the fans, you know.
But you did show up late!
Next time, make it for the kickoff!
I'm counting on ya!
Hey there, Aoi!
I'm Aoi Kaneko from Soccer Every.
Do you have a minute to talk to me about the game today?
What's going on?
At least that's what I wanted to say.
But I'm kind of late for another interview.
It's a different Metro League matchup.
But please, let me leave you my card.
Let's get together sometime.
Now, wait just a minute there, kid.
Are you trying to contact a player without going through the proper channels?
There's another Metro League match?
Yeah, it's, uh, the Tokyo Musashino Youth match.
Musashino Youth?
Uh-huh, there's sudden improvements got everyone talking.
Ashito!
Oh?
Uh, what is it, Otomo?
Ashito, we have a problem.
Huh?
Got a minute?
Sure, why?
In the next match...
I, uh, I don't want you to play me.
My confidence is shut.
He doesn't want to play at all?
Tachibana actually said that.
Yeah, man.
It's because he'd have to play against his old team.
Tokyo Musashino.
Otomo, let's go watch their game today.
What?
We'll take Tachibana too.
It'll be good for us to know what kind of game they play.
Let's see what they're made of.
Next time on Awashi, what we lack.